Salman Siddique Khan

salmansiddique.khan@gmail.com � +1 (669) 295-8448 � Houston, TX � Personal Webpage � Google Scholar

I am a Postdoctoral Associate in the Department of ECE, Rice University with >5 years of experience in computational photography, computer vision and deep learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rice University

Aug. 2023 – Present

Postdoctoral Associate Houston, TX

Worked with Prof. Ashok Veeraraghavan and Prof. Ashutosh Sabharwal

• Developed: (a) Coded dual-pixel camera (**CADS**) that is **6%** better than conventional dual-pixel cameras for RGB and Depth estimates. (b) Near-eye lensless gaze-tracking system with a dataset of more than **20k pairs**. (c) Few-shot coronary risk estimator from non-gated CTs using **Segment Anything Model (SAM)**

NEC Labs America Jun. 2022 – Dec. 2022

Research Intern

San Jose, CA

Worked in the Media Analytics team with Dr. Manmohan Chandraker and Dr. Francesco Pittaluga.

• Developed: (a) Lensless optical encryption camera called **OpEnCam**. (b) **Dense Prediction Transformer** (**DPT**) based cryptanalysis of encryption cameras

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology Madras, India

Jul. 2018 – Jul. 2023

Ph.D., Electrical Engineering, Advisor: Prof. Kaushik Mitra

- Thesis: Learning-based Scene Reconstruction, Design and Inference in Lensless Imaging
 - Developed: (a) Physics-inspired neural nets (FlatNet), for lensless reconstruction that offers better image quality and is 25x faster than SOTA. (b) Encryption camera (OpEnCam) that is ~ 17% more secure than existing encryption cameras
 - o Won Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship India

National Institute of Technology Rourkela, India

Jul. 2014 - Jul. 2018

B. Tech., Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Salman S. Khan et al. (2024) "OpEnCam: Lensless Optical Encryption Camera." to appear in IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging (TCI)
- B. Ghanekar, Salman S. Khan et.al. "Passive Snapshot Coded Aperture Dual-Pixel RGB-D Imaging."
 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR 2024)
- Salman S. Khan et al. (2020) "FlatNet: Towards photorealistic scene reconstruction from lensless measurements." IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (PAMI)
- Salman S. Khan et al. "Towards photorealistic reconstruction of highly multiplexed lensless images." IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV 2019)

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Reviewer for: IEEE TPAMI, IEEE TCI, IEEE OJSP, Optics Express; CVPR, ECCV, WACV, ICASSP

SKILLS

Experienced in: computational imaging, computer vision, inverse problems, deep learning, image restoration, vision and language models and medical imaging; PyTorch, Tensorflow, scikit-learn; Docker, Linux, GitHub, BASH